

### Victoria Kush

Phone: 71 46 53 72

Email: victoria.v.kush@gmail.com

### **PROFILE**

I am an ambitious problem solver with a passion for web-development, and I would like to join a team of like-minded developers. I am thorough and precise in everything I do and have a keen interest in technology, web development, and user experience. As someone who takes responsibility for their personal development, I am continually evaluating and upgrading my skills. I am boundlessly creative and relentlessly attentive to detail. I am passionate about creating beautiful, attractive, intuitive, efficient and user-friendly websites.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER IN YELLOW UMWELT From March 2023

- Working with React / Tailwind CSS/ NextJs / Netlify / TypeScript /Storyblok / Xd / Storybook.
- Worked closely with design, product and backend teams to create web products and deliver digital assets for the website to ensure a harmonized digital representation.
- Created adaptable and 100% reusable solutions for future use, translated business requirements into code.
- Optimized 7+ applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- Led troubleshooting, fixed bugs and other issues, updated sites troughout production lifecircle.

#### FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER IN AKQA

March 2022 - March 2023

- Working with React / Tailwind CSS/ Theme UI / TypeScript / Docker / Figma / Storybook / Contentful / Jest.
- Worked closely with other departments to facilitate the solving of day-to-day challenges.
- Building best-in-class applications, serving users on the modern web landscape.
- Provided technical answers and effective technical decisions to solve client problems.

### FULL-STACK DEVELOPER IN HUMAN HOTEL

April 2021 - February 2022

- Working with React / Redux / Docker / GraphQL / Bootstrap / Figma / Storybook.
- Identified new needs and requirements and developed web products that focused on usability and user experience.
- Created clean, maintainable, cross-browser compatible code from mockups.
- Changed page loading speed from 3 to 1 second to improve web perforance.

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER IN FIZZIT

#### Septembere 2020 - March 2021

- Working with React / ReactNative / CSS.
- Working on building a responsive company website.
- Develop web pages and content consistent with Fizzit branding guidelines.
- Research new and existing tools/techniques to keep programs current and relevant.
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API.
- Teamwork & Experience communicating with a creative and ambitious development team.

### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER SELF-EMPLOYED

#### From February 2019

- Working with CSS / JavaScript / React / NodeJs / Google Analytics / WordPress
- Built fully responsive websites with interactivity and a focus on user experience.
- Have maintained websites, checking for errors, broken links and improving sites performance.
- Bug fixing and sites support.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILL

- Great problem-solving skills, strategic thinking and technical skills.
- Effective oral communication skills, organizational skills and attention to detail.
- Excellent interpersonal, communication and crossgroup collaboration skills.
- Proficient understanding of web markup, including knowledge of modern HTML/ CSS.
- Responsive design skills, knowledge of how to mix of flexible grids and layouts, images and how to use of CSS media queries.
- Mastery of advanced animation techniques: CSS, SVG, canvas.

- Experience with general User Experience concepts and the ability to design highly effective user interfaces.
- Fair understanding of JavaScript programming and DOM manipulation.
- Coding in ES6 standards for maintainability, readability.
- Git. Experience keep the track of modifications with a comment, merging and branching strategies, managing merge conflicts.
- Great understanding of React.js and its core principles, React Hooks.
- Experience in TypeScript and NextJs.

- Adequate knowledge how servers work as well as APIs, MySQL, the database.
- Experience in creating user validation forms and sending data to server using RESTful services.
- Understanding how core Node.js works. Experience deploying application with Netlify.
- Coding the Figma and Xd mockups.
- Thorough understanding of Agile methodologies and principles. Familiarity with Atlassian Tools (Jira, Confluence).
- Good knowledge of technical SEO best practices.

### **EDUCATION**

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT - COPENHAGEN. 2020

The curriculum includes HTML /CSS /Git /CLI /Javascript /NodeJS /ExpressJS /React etc.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE V. N. KARAZIN KHARKIV NATIONAL UNIVERSITY. 2012 – 2014

Ph.D. IN PSYCHOLOGY V. N. KARAZIN KHARKIV NATIONAL UNIVERSITY. 2008 – 2012

## **CERTIFICATES**

- Responsive Web Design Certification by freeCodeCamp.
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification by freeCodeCamp.
- Umbraco Fundamentals.
- App Development Certification by Shopify.
- Product Fundamentals Certification by Shopify.
- Contentful Certification Program.
- HackerRank silver Problem Solving badge.